Finding aid to the Smith College publications and publications records CA.MS.01006
Smith College Archives
Smith College publications and publications records
1872-2017
Smith College Archives
Smith College.
CA.MS.01006
34.5 linear feet (51 containers)
6 website
Publications records consist of pamphlets, brochures, booklets, transparencies, college calendars, directory catalogue, faculty and staff publications, admission marketing material, publicity materials and programs for major college-wide events (such as Rally Day), the Smith Alumnae Quarterly, The Alumnae Register, the Smith College Catalogue, The Annual Report of the President of Smith College and Meridians.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation. In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
These materials were transferred to College Archives in 1986, 1991, 2008, and 2018.
Biographical / Historical
Publications are produced by the College Relations staff and range from brochures and booklets to large-scale projects such as the admission viewbook and the Smith Alumnae Quarterly. The focus is external (off-campus) college relations.
The Smith Alumnae Quarterly has been published from 1909 to present. Meridians has been published from 2000 to present. The Alumnae Register is published every 3 years, from 1893 to present. The Annual Report of the President of Smith College has been published from 1875-present. The Smith College Catalogue has been published from 1915-present.
Other Finding Aids
The collection has container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu
Scope and Contents
Publications records consist of pamphlets, brochures, booklets, transparencies, college calendars, directory catalogue, faculty and staff publications, admission marketing material, publicity materials and programs for major college-wide events (such as Rally Day), the Smith Alumnae Quarterly, The Alumnae Register, the Smith College Catalogue, The Annual Report of the President of Smith College and Meridians.
Conditions Governing Access
Until we move into New Neilson in early 2021, collections are stored in multiple locations and may take up to 48 hours to retrieve. Researchers are strongly encouraged to contact Special Collections (specialcollections@smith.edu) at least a week in advance of any planned visits so that boxes may be retrieved for them in a timely manner.
Smith College.; Alumnae Association
- A - CE (Box 615)
- Ch - E (Box 615.1)
- "Facts About Smith/Facts at Fingertips" (Open) (Box 615.2)
- "Facts at Fingertips" (Box 615.3)
- F - H (Box 615.4)
- I - H (Box 616)
- N - S (Box 616.1)
- T - Z (Box 616.1a)
- Publications from Admissions Office
  - A - I (Box 616.2)
  - J - P (Box 616.3)
  - Q - Z (Box 616.4)
  - Admissions Picturebook, 1924-1970 (Box 616.5)
  - Admissions Picturebook/Viewbook, 1983-2007 (Box 616.6)
- Calendars (Illustrated)
  - Calendars (Illustrated), 1894-1941 (Box 617)
  - Calendars (Illustrated), 1942-2000 (Box 618)
  - Calendars (Illustrated) and Calendars (Appointments), 1989-2004 (Box 618.1)
  - Calendars (Illustrated) - oversize (Box 618.2)
- Annual Bulletin (Dup set) - Official Circulars, 1872-1914 (Box 619.1)
- Smith College Annual Bulletin, 1913-1940 (Box 619.2)
- Commencement Week Programs (Box 620)
- Courses of Study/Schedule of Classes (Box 621)
- Directories (Box 621.1)
- Interim Directories, 1971-1992 (Box 622)
- President's Reports
  - Typed copy and manuscript, 1875-1896 (Box 630)
  - Additional copies, 1896-1982 (Box 630.1)
  - Additional copies, 1982-2001 (Box 630.2)
- Smith College Weekly Bulletin
  - SCWB, 1904-1922 (Box 638.2)
  - SCWB, 1922-1928 (Box 638.3)
  - SCWB, 1928-1935 (Box 638.4)
  - SCWB, 1935-1942 (Box 638.5)
  - SCWB, 1942-1950 (Box 638.6)
  - SCWB, 1950-1955 (Box 631)
  - SCWB, 1955-1960 (Box 632)
  - SCWB, 1960-1964 (Box 633)
  - SCWB, 1964-1969 (Box 634)
  - SCWB, 1969-1974 (Box 635)
  - SCWB, 1974-1978 (Box 636)
  - SCWB, 1978-1981 (Box 637)
  - SCWB, 1981-1985 (Box 638)
  - SCWB, 1985-1987 (Box 638.1)
- Weekly Calendar, Acamedia, 1987 - 1991; 2/28/1991 - 12/16/1993 (Box 638.7)
- NewsSmith, 1993 - 2010 (Box 638.8)
- Acamedia
  - Acamedia, 1994-1999 (Box 638.9)
  - Acamedia, 1999-2004 (Box 638.9a)
- Smith Connections (Box 638.9b)
- Administrative files of Meridians: A Journal of Feminism, Race, and Transnationalism, 1996-2017; Meridians Journal Office; 4.5 linear feet (3 record cartons, 1 regular document box, 1/2 regular document box, 1 oversize box. Digital media are in box 1.)
  Scope and Contents
  Business files related to the administration and production of the journal Meridians, a joint venture between Smith College and published by Indiana University Press.
  Computer media
  - E-mail correspondence, 2002-2010 (Box 1)
  - Financial records, 2002-2008 (Box 1)
  - Contracts, 2000-2003 (Box 1)
  - Retreat, 2017 (Box 1)
  - "Trafficking Sex: Politics, Policy, Personhood" conference, 2013 (Box 1)
  - Ford Foundation, 2002-2004 (Box 1)
  - Subscription list, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Potential readers, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Brenda Marie Osbey event, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Art work, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Circulation report, 2011 (Box 1)
  - Roundtable event planning, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Copyright information, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Digital archives, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Computer media: 1 CD and 2 3.5 floppy disks, 2003-2005 (Box 1)
  - Planning and correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 2)
  - Agendas and retreats, 1998-2003 (Box 2)
  - Contracts, 2000-2005 (Box 2)
  - Advertising, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Budget and Board organizing, 1998-2012 (Box 2)
  - Meridians style sheet and submission guidelines (Box 2)
  - Marketing and advertising, 1998-2003 (Box 2)
  - Travel and finances, 2003-2011 (Box 2)
  - Grant proposals, 2014 (Box 2)
  - Budgets, 2008-2011 (Box 2)
  - When and Where I Enter event, 2016 (Box 2)
  - Meridians inaugural conference, 2001 (Box 3)
  - "Women, Girls and HIV/AIDS in Africa and the African Diaspora" conference, Spelman College, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Kahn Institute session on trafficking notes, 2012 (Box 3)
  - Photographs, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Handouts, flyers, and notecards (Box 3)
  - Board nominees, 1999 (Box 3)
  - National Women's Studies Association/Women of Color Caucus website, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Ford grant, 2000-2003 (Box 3)
  - Inaugural conference and early planning, 1999-2001 (Box 3)
  - Journal production, 2009 (Box 3)
  - Local board meetings, 2000-2002 (Box 3)
  - Production schedule, 2017 (Box 4)
  - Duke University Press proposal, 2017 (Box 4)
  - Indiana University Press contract, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Meridians Symposium: State of the Field, 2016 (Box 4)
  - Ford Foundation, 2000-2003 (Box 4)
  - Women's Studies K-12 panel, 2010 (Box 4)
  - Marketing, 2001-2002 (Box 4)
  - Book reviews, 2001-2002 (Box 4)
  - Indiana University Press report, 2008-2009 (Box 4)
  - Meridians meetings, 2000-2001 (Box 4)
  - Smith Alumnae Quarterly advertisement, 2001 (Box 4)
  - National Board nominations, 2003 (Box 5)
  - Founding proposals, 1996-1998 (Box 5)
  - Budget, 2000-2001 (Box 5)
  - Faxed contracts, 2012-2013 (Box 5)
  - Status report, 2016 (Box 5)
  - Poetry solicitations, 2001 (Box 5)
  - Event posters, 2009-2010 (Box 6)
- Smith College websites
  The Smith College archived websites includes the official college website, news, and social media managed by the Office of College Relations. Additional web content is added to the archive on a regular basis. Once the initial capture of a website is completed, periodic captures are conducted as long as the site is active.
  - Smith College website, first captured 2012; 1 website
  - eDigest, first captured 2015; 1 website
  - Grécourt Gate (news), first captured 2012; 1 website
  - Insight, first captured 2015; 1 website
  - NewsSmith, first captured 2015; 1 website
  - Smith College Facebook, first captured 2015; 1 website
  - Smith College Twitter feed, First captured 2019; 1 website
  - Smith College YouTube channel, First captured 2019; 1 website